A Guide to the Roller Family Papers 1828-1974
Virginia Historical Society
- Mary Caroline Cabell (1866-1942) papers, 1853-1940
  - Correspondence, 1899-1940, ca. 600 items (Box 8-12)
    Prominent correspondents include Elizabeth Henry (Roller) Bottimore (early letters are from Mary Caroline at Inglewood, Nelson co., Va., to Elizabeth as a child living in Harrisonburg; later letters are from Elizabeth in Richmond, Va., just before and after her marriage. Topics include family activities in Nelson co., and activities of Elizabeth and her sisters Lucy Cabell Roller and Anne Woolston (Roller) Pyle), Elsie (Hughes) Cabell (of Tom's Creek, Va., wife of Somers Eubank Cabell, discussing their courtship, marriage, and family life), John Willis Cabell (while attending Roanoke College, Salem, Va., 1899-1900, teaching and working for railroads in Kentucky, 1900-1902, and living in Charlotte, N.C., with his family, 1920-1921), Royal Eubank Cabell (while attending Princeton University, 1898, working as a lawyer in Richmond, Va., as Commissioner of Internal Revenue in Washington, D.C., and after his return to his Richmond law practice, concerning the health of his brother, Patrick Henry Carey Cabell, the activities of the Roller children and the settlement of John Edwin Roller's estate, and family news), Somers Eubank Cabell (while attending Virginia Polytechnic Institute, 1903-1906, and working for General Electric in Schnectady, N.Y.), Annie Woolston (Cabell) Flowers (while teaching in Kentucky and Vandemere, N.C., detailing life in Nelson co., illnesses among family members, plans for family weddings, including hers in 1905, and her life in Vandemere after her marriage), Margaret Etta (Cabell) Matthews (chiefly from early in her marriage to Rev. Nathan Matthews and while living in Liberia, and later while living in Danvers, Mass., concerning her husband's abuse and her quandary over whether to leave him), Anne Woolston (Roller) Pyle (early letters concern her childhood in Harrisonburg, Va., and, after her mother's death in 1914, her education and social life in Richmond, Va.), Lucy Brown (Cabell) Roller (chiefly after her marriage to John E. Roller and while living in Harrisonburg, Va., letters written to her from Mary Caroline concerning life in Nelson co., including the comings and goings of Cabell and Micklem family members and boarders, marriages, illnesses, deaths, servant troubles, the activities of sister Margaret Etta (Cabell) Matthews, including her return from Africa for the births of her children, requests for the purchase of various items of clothing, and the well-being of Lucy's three daughters), and Lucy Cabell Roller (while living as a child in Harrisonburg, Va., and after the deaths of her parents, at school and living in Richmond, Va.).
    Bates, Minnie
    Bottimore, Elizabeth Henry (Roller)
    Boyce, H. G.
    Bradshaw, Katherine E. S.
    Cabell, Anne E.
    Cabell, Anne Elizabeth (Moore)
    Cabell, Anne (Renfro) Tomlinson
    Cabell, Charles Lorraine
    Cabell, Charles Patrick
    Cabell, Edmonia Elizabeth
    Cabell, Elsie (Hughes)
    Cabell, John W.
    Cabell, Louisa Withers
    Cabell, Margaret
    Cabell, Mary
    Calloway, Patrick Henry
    Coleman, Frances LeBaron
    Coleman, Rutherfoord
    Coleman, Samuel Henry
    Cook, W. E. (Mrs.)
    Dawson, Gertrude H.
    Dortch, Jeffress Samuel
    Eichelberger, Lillie M.
    Field, John P.
    Gardner, Francis Kinlock Nelson
    Gardner, Virginia Cabell
    Glover, Emma S.
    Grattan, Frances Lewis (Roller)
    Guy, Scott
    Herrell, Hattie (Eubank)
    Horsley, Clara Lee
    Horsley, Eliza Richardson
    James, Caroline Elizabeth (Micklem)
    Kirkpatrick, Lorraine (Mrs.)
    Lawson, Ethel M.
    Lee, Virginia L.
    Lemmon, Edward Travis
    Lienan, Oscar B.
    Lorraine, Charles
    Mason, Bessie H.
    Mason, S. B.
    Massie, Barksdale
    Massie, William Withers
    Matthews, Patrick Cabell
    Micklem, Alice
    Moore, Robert T.
    Morton, Blanche (Mckay)
    Moss, Helen Carlton (Gardner)
    Mundy, C. D.
    Mundy, Ida C.
    Pence, Mary Gertrude
    Phillips, Gillie
    Pyle, Anne Woolston (Roller)
    Randolph, Louisa H.
    Rich, Arnold Hoyer
    Rich, Ruth (Moncure) See Rich, Arnold Hoyer
    Sheringham, Helen F.
    Sidbury, Helen M.
    Simpson, Mary
    Simpson, Walter
    Turpin, Edna Henry Lee
    Waters, Louisa Anderson
    Winold, Susie A.
    Wormeley, Lucy DuVal
    Yonce, Jo (Mrs.)
    Daughters of the American Revolution. Virginia. Massanutton Chapter
    Lynchburg National Bank & Trust Co., Lynchburg, Va.
    Miller & Roads, Incorporated, Richmond, Va.
    Nelson Parish, Nelson co., Va.
    Traveler's Insurance Company, Hartford, Conn.
    Arranged alphabetically by correspondent:
    Box 8: A - Cabell
    Box 9: Calloway - L
    Box 10: M - P
    Box 11: R - Roller, Lucy Brown (Cabell)
    Box 12: Roller, Lucy Cabell - end
  - Financial materials, 1931-1932, 15 items (Box 13)
    Include scattered accounts and a check stub book.
  - School materials, 1853-1932, 7 items (Box 13)
    Include an account book, 1915-1916, for the Inglewood school; an issue of "The Album," student magazine published by Hollins Institute, 1883; and Mitchell's School Atlas (Philadelphia, 1853).
  - Scrapbook n.d. (Box 13)
    Contains engravings, lines of verse, and prose.
  - Miscellaneous materials, ca. 100 items (Box 13)
    Includes calling cards, wedding invitations, tombstone inscriptions, and advertising materials.
- Anne Woolston (Cabell) Flowers (1869-1958) correspondence, 1890-1951, 116 items (Box 14)
  Correspondence of Anne Woolston (Cabell) Flowers, chiefly with her sisters, Margaret Etta (Cabell) Matthews (concerning her life in Africa, 1904), and Lucy Brown (Cabell) Roller (including letters to Lucy from Anne describing her teaching experiences in Timberville, Va., Scotland, Ky., and Vandemere, N.C.).
  Gardner, Alice
  Pence, Gertrude
  Wierman, Rosamond
- John Edwin Roller (1844-1918) papers, 1835-1918
  - Correspondence, 1870-1916, ca. 400 items (Box 15-18)
    Correspondence of Gen. John Edwin "Ned" Roller, chiefly falling into two periods, 1870-1872, concerning Roller's plans to run for election to the Virginia House of Delegates, and 1895-1916, concerning his marriage in 1896 to Lucy Brown Cabell, and after, concerning his family life. Many correspondents from the earlier period give details of political sentiment on the local level (see William Withers Adams, William B. W. Brooking, Henry B. Harnsberger, Henry Marcellus Keyser, John Marshall McCue, William Merry Perkins, E. D. Pettit, Charles Summerville Rohr, Lawrence Royster, Ezra Eugenius Stickley, William Harrison Triplett, John Richard Wingfield, Charles Junius Woodson, and others). Non-family letters from the later period are typically letters of congratulations on his marriage.
    Letters to Lucy Brown Cabell during their courtship discuss the objections of Roller's teenage daughters to their marriage, the age difference between Roller and Lucy, and Lucy's father's objections to the proposed marriage settlement. Letters after their marriage are chiefly exchanged while Roller is traveling on business and during Lucy's annual visits to her family at Inglewood, Nelson co., and discuss their children and domestic issues.
    Letters to Roller from daughters Frances Lewis (Roller) Grattan and Margaret Stuart (Roller) Cannady Ogilvie Merryman concern their attendance at Woman's College, Frederick, Md. (now Hood College), in particular social activities and financial needs. Letters from Roller to daughters Elizabeth Henry (Roller) Bottimore, Anne Woolston (Roller) Pyle, and Lucy Cabell Roller contain family news and fatherly advice while they are away visiting Cabell relatives.
    Also included is scattered correspondence with Roller's brothers, Oliver Brown Roller, Peter Samuel Roller, Robert Douglas Roller, and William Wirt Roller, largely concerning the financing of their respective educations. Oliver attended the Virginia Military Institute, Lexington, Va. Peter attended Augusta Military Academy. Robert attended the Episcopal Theological Seminary of Virginia.
    Adams, William Withers
    Apple, Gertrude (Harner)
    Ashby, John Woodville
    Blume, Jack
    Boteler, Alexander Robinson
    Bradford, Taliaferro C.
    Brooking, William B. W.
    Brown, Alexander
    Brown, D. D.
    Brown, Oliver Matthews
    Campbell, James Lawrence
    Campbell, Samuel Sprigg
    Carichoff, Lewis A.
    Clarke, Bettie J.
    Comer, Christian
    Conrad, Edward Smith
    Cosby, H. P.
    Craun, John Samuel
    Daniel, John Warwick
    Danner, Margaret
    Echols, Edward
    Ellington, R. J.
    Ergenbright, R. R.
    FauntLeRoy, Emily Henry
    Fitzsimons, J. F.
    Flannagan, William Walker
    Fleming, James P.
    French, Samuel Bassett
    Funk, P. G.
    Funkhouser, Robert Daniel
    Gilkeson, Francis
    Gordon, Armistead C.
    Gordon, Lulu E.
    Grabill, John H.
    Grim, William
    Grimsley, Daniel Amon
    Gum, John E.
    Guy, John Henry
    Hale, Giles William Bruce
    Hanger, James Marshall
    Hannah, Samuel Baldwin
    Harnsberger, Henry B.
    Harris, Frederick
    Helms, R. A.
    Hendrick, D. S.
    Heneberger, Lucy B.
    Hickman, Joseph T. (Dr.)
    Hinde, Hugh
    Hoge, Charles E.
    Holladay, Alexander Quarles
    Huffman, Emanuel
    Isaacs, Sallie E. (Roller) Richardson
    Jones, Hilary Pollard
    Jones, John Robert See Huffman, Emanuel
    Keyser, Henry Marcellus
    Leake, Andrew Kean
    Letcher, Samuel Houston
    Lewis, John Francis
    McCue, John Marshall
    MacQueary, Emma Clarkson (Harris)
    Martin, Helen Reimensnyder
    Meem, John Gaw
    Michie, [?]
    Miller, Edwin Lunn
    Minor, Carter Nelson Berkeley
    Moffett, P. B.
    Morris, James Cheston
    Odell, W. S.
    Page, Thomas Nelson
    Patterson, Benjamin G.
    Pence, Milton
    Perkins, William Merry
    Pettit, E. D.
    Pettit, William Beverly
    Preston, Robert John
    Pyle, Ann Woolston (Roller)
    Richardson, William Harvie
    Riddell, Thomas J.
    Rohr, Harrison
    Rohr, Charles Summerville
    Rohr, William S.
    [Roller, Edwin]
    Roller, Oliver Brown
    Roller, Peter Samuel
    Roller, Robert Douglas
    Roller, William Wirt
    Root, E. D.
    Royal, William Lawrence
    Royster, Lawrence
    Scott, William Wallace
    Smith, Francis Lee
    Spangler, S. S.
    Spindle, Robert H.
    Spitler, Mann
    Stickley, Ezra Eugenius
    Stonesifer, James B.
    Strasburger, [?]
    Stribling, Francis Taliaferro
    Stringfellow, Franklin See Roller, Robert Douglas
    Stuart, Flora (Cooke)
    Trevey, Jacob Cowan
    Triplett, William Harrison
    Turley, C. M.
    Walker, Charles Duy
    Walker, Richard Frederick
    White, William L.
    Wingfield, John Richard
    Woods, Micajah
    Woodson, Charles Junius
    Woolston, Clarence Herbert
    Wright, Thomas Roane Barnes
    Young, William Townsend
    Lauriat (Charles E.) Company, Boston, Mass.
    Friends of Greeley & Brown, Luray, Va.
    Marshall Literary Society, Mercersburg College, Pa.
    Centennial Committee of Philadelphia, Pa.
    Republican Party. Congressional Executive Committee
    Settlers' And Immigrants' Aid Society, Norfolk, Va.
    Virginia. Auditor of Public Accounts
    Virginia Historical Society, Richmond, Va.
    Virginia. Military institute, Lexington, Va.
    Walsh (Rees) Law & General Bookseller, Philadelphia, Pa.
    Box 15: A - G
    Box 16: H - Roller, Edwin
    Box 17: Roller, Lucy Brown
    Box 18: Roller, Lucy Cabell - end
  - Financial materials, 1894-1918, 15 items (Box 19)
    Includes accounts, 1894-1918, chiefly with Harrisonburg, Va., merchants, and including protests, 1912, against a note given to Lucy Brown (Cabell) Roller.
  - School materials 1866, n.d., 5 items (Box 19)
    Includes a list of students in Roller's class at the Virginia Military Institute, Lexington, Va.; and examination questions from law classes at the University of Virginia, 1866.
  - Historical manuscripts 1824, 1835, 1868, 4 items (Box 19)
    Includes scattered letters of David Crockett, Browns Hotel, [Tex.], 1835; Samuel Houston, Washington, D.C., 1824; and William Gilmore Simms, Charleston, S.C., and New York, N.Y, 1868.
  - Miscellaneous materials, ca. 50 items (Box 19)
    Includes wedding invitations, dinner invitations, commencement invitations for Woman's College of Frederick, Md. (now Hood College) and the Virginia Female Institute, Staunton, Va. (now Stuart Hall), responses to invitations, calling cards, and commissions, 1866 and 1868, appointing Roller vice-president of Mt. Crawford and Rockingham co. councils, Virginia State Council of the Friends of Temperance.
- Lucy Brown (Cabell) Roller (1871-1914) papers, 1888-1913
  - Correspondence, 1888-1914, ca. 800 items (Box 20-26)
    Correspondence of Lucy Brown "Lily" (Cabell) Roller of Harrisonburg, Va., chiefly with her family and female friends discussing family activities (marriages, births, and deaths), social activities, and visits. Prominent correspondents include her daughter Elizabeth Henry (Roller) Bottimore (while accompanying her father, John Edwin Roller, on trips west, 1907 and 1908, and visiting the Cabells at "Inglewood," Nelson co., Va.), brother John Willis Cabell (while living at "Inglewood," Nelson co., Va., attending Roanoke College, Salem, Va., while working on railroads in Tennessee, and in Richmond, Va., working for his brother, Patrick Henry Carey Cabell, lawyer for the Travelers Insurance Company, concerning news of family and friends, social activities in Nelson co., railroad construction in Tennessee, and his engagement to Anne Elizabeth "Bessie" Moore); sister-in-law Lillian Hoge (Lorraine) Cabell (of Richmond, Va., and Washington, D.C., wife of Royal Eubank Cabell, discussing her children and social life in Richmond; letter of 1905 November 19 includes illustrations of children in various poses); cousin Lucy G. Cabell (of Norwood, Wingina, and "Union Hill," Nelson co., Va., giving news of Cabell relations, discussing the health of her invalid mother and brother-in-law, and discussing her embroidery work), cousin Mary Holmes (McGuire) Cabell (of Waynesboro, Va., concerning her domestic life), Virginia C. Gardner (of Valley Farm, Broaddus, Va., and other places, concerning her work as a school teacher, her recreational reading, mutual friends, clothing, social activities, the births of Lucy's children, and various Cabell marriages), Minnie (Cox) Graham (while visiting Summerville, S.C., and Rockbridge Alum Springs, Va., and while living at Tazewell, Va., after her marriage to Judge Samuel Cecil Graham, concerning her social activities at Rockbridge Alum Springs, her views on Arctic exploration, her decision to break her engagement in order to accept Judge Graham's proposal, her wedding plans, and the birth of a daughter); step-daughter Frances Lewis "Lewie" (Roller) Grattan (while attending the Woman's College, Frederick, Md. [now Hood College], 1896-1897, and visiting relatives along the Eastern seaboard, concerning school life, clothing, and social activities), Lucy Bailey Heneberger (of Harrisonburg, Va., concerning the Massanutten Chapter of the Daughters of the American Revolution), cousin Caroline Elizabeth "Carrie" (Micklem) James (of "Roseland," Nelson co., Va., and at "Inglewood," Nelson co., Va., while attending Mary Caroline Cabell's school, discussing family life), sister Margaret "Etta" (Cabell) Matthews (while living with her missionary husband at Cape Mount and St. John's Station, Liberia, describing her daily life in Africa, 1904-1906 and 1909-1910, and while living at home at "Inglewood," Nelson co., Va., discussing family news), stepdaughter Margaret "Marco" Stuart (Roller) Cannady Ogilvie Merryman (while attending Woman's College, Frederick, Md. [now Hood College] and Virginia Female Institute, Staunton, Va., discussing school life, clothing and social activities), sister-in-law Caroline (Booker) Roller (of Charleston, W. Va., wife of Rev. Robert Douglas Roller, discussing family life), daughter Lucy Cabell Roller (during visits to Cabell relatives in Nelson co., Va., discussing social activities and family news), and Emma Louise (Lorraine) Sanders (of Richmond, Va., discussing social and family life and the activities of Frances Lewis (Roller) Grattan).
    Act, Elizabeth Hanson
    Amiss, John B. (Mrs.)
    Anderson, Joseph Reid
    Armentrout, H. A.
    Ayres, Andrew Hart
    Ayres, Davis (Mr. and Mrs.)
    Baer, Emma M.
    Baer, M. G.
    Bayless, D. B.
    Beery, Nora
    Bentley, Elizabeth Lee
    Bentley, Mary Gray
    Bradley, Sue
    Briscoe, D. L.
    Brooking, Esther F. C.
    Brooking, Rosa
    Brooking, Robert U.
    Brown, Mayo Cabell
    Burkhardt, William Hulliher
    Cabell, Alice
    Cabell, Caroline A.
    Cabell, Ruth Holmes
    Cabell, Sallie Jordan Laidley
    Cabell, Virginia Lehew
    Call, Lucy Lee
    Calwell, Alberta
    Calwell, Frances Antoinette (Roller)
    Cannaday, John Egerton
    Carter, Bettie J. C.
    Clarken, Alice Shriver
    Conrad, Mary Lynn
    Cornell, Josepha R.
    Cornell, Mary E.
    Cornell, Mary L.
    Cowan, S. Alice
    Dean, Mattie
    Dean, William
    Dechert, Bessie
    de Soucy, Pierre
    Devier, C.
    Devier, Hortense
    Early, Mollie J.
    Echard, Carolynne
    Ellis, Josiah R.
    Ellis, Lucy A. W.
    Fauntleroy, Bettie S.
    Fauntleroy, Mary B.
    [Firth], Roberta L.
    Fitzpatrick, J.
    Funkhouser, A. P. (Mrs.)
    Gantt, N. Horsley
    Gardner, Virginia Constance
    Gibson, Robert A.
    Gilham, John A. P.
    Glover, Ada
    Goodwin, Ella Harvie
    Goodwin, E. L.
    Goodwin, Lettie R.
    Graham, Minnie (Cox)
    Gwatkin, W. E.
    Haas, T. N. (Mrs.)
    Hanckel, William C.
    Harris, Anna
    Harris, Elizabeth Randolph
    Heath, F. E. R.
    Heetzel, Susan R.
    Hendrick, Elizabeth C.
    Hendrick, Ree
    Heneberger, Lucy Bailey
    Henry, R. R.
    Herring, Charles Griffin
    Herring, Elizabeth Gould
    Herring, Lillian
    Herring, Mary
    Hill, Annie A.
    Hoffman, [?] (Mrs.)
    Holladay, Syme Ayres
    Hollingsworth, C. M.
    Hollingsworth, Charles
    Hotchkiss, Alice
    Hubard, Alice Wilson
    Hubard, Isa C.
    Hubard, Lila C.
    Jackson, H. M.
    John, Edith
    Johnson, Ella M.
    Jones, Laura
    Landers, Emma C.
    Lewis, J. M.
    Lewis, M. Botts
    Loewner, A. W.
    Logan, Bettie C. See Logan, Margaret
    Logan, Conrad T.
    Logan, Margaret
    Lorraine, Charles Cabell
    Lorraine, Martha Evelyn Bohannon
    McCabe, Cora Ross
    McClelland, E. L. (Mr. and Mrs.)
    McKay, Roberta First
    McVeigh, Charles S.
    Marko, Helen
    Martz, Stella Bowcock
    Mash, Emily M.
    Mason, Robert I.
    Mathewes, Mary Hubard
    Matthews, Jessie Woods (Higginbotham)
    Micklem, Bella
    Micklem, Ernest
    Micklem, Margaret Etta (Eubank) See Micklem, Earnest
    Milburn, Etherbert
    Mosby, Ella F.
    Neff, B. M.
    Nicodemus, A. W.
    Ott, Elizabeth E.
    Palmer, Alice Cabell
    Palmer, Margaret
    Pattison, Marguerite S.
    Pattison, Mary Stuart
    Paul, Bessie
    Paul, K. S.
    Paul, Virginia Marion
    Paxton, Isabella Crenshaw
    Pence, Caroline Heater
    Pence, Lizzie E.
    Pence, M[amie] N.
    Pence, Sallie
    Points, William J.
    Price, Mary
    Proctor, Sallie J.
    Prugh, Charlotte A.
    Pugh, Bessie
    Purcell, Bessie Heaton
    Ranson, Eleanor S.
    Richardson, Sarah Bradford
    Robertson, Ellen Booker (Roller)
    Robinson, Caroline May (Roller)
    Robinson, Evelyn C.
    Rodes, Adeline V.
    Rodgers, Lucy Hooke
    Roller, Alberta
    Roller, Caroline (Booker)
    Rothget, [?] (Mrs.)
    Rutherfoord, Jane M.
    St. John, Edith (Mrs.)
    Sanders, Emma Louise (Lorraine)
    Schmidt, Marie L.
    Seddon, Elsie
    Shacklett, Fannie
    Simpson, Mabel Margaret
    Sipe, Marion M.
    Smiley, Cora L.
    Smith, Essie W.
    Smith, Henrietta
    Sprinkel, W. G.
    Stringfellow, Frank
    Tantum, W. R. (Mrs.)
    Van Lear, [?]
    Van Pelt, R. A.
    Waddill, Mattie
    White, Robert
    Wiley, Georgia B.
    Wilson, Alice
    Woodward, Anna B.
    Wunder, Grace
    Yerger, O. M.
    Bailey, Banks & Biddle Co., Philadelphia, Pa.
    Bayless Stove & Range Co., Cincinnati, Ohio
    Century Co., Union Square, N.Y.
    Churchman Company, New York, N.Y.
    Emmanuel Protestant Episcopal Church, Harrisonburg, Va.
    Ferguson (L. M.), Columbus, Ohio
    Higgins & Seither, New York, N.Y.
    Hines (Junius) & Son Baltimore, Md.
    Knox (Charles B.), Johnstown, N.Y.
    Low (D.) & Co., Salem, Mass.
    Meserole (W. A.) & Bro., Harrisonburg, Va.
    Nichols (Miss J. D.), Commissionaire, Philadelphia, Pa.
    Palais Royal, Washington, D.C.
    Paul Revere Memorial Association, Boston, Mass.
    Wanamaker (John), Philadelphia, Pa.
    Wells (Miss), Church Embroidery, Geneva, N.Y.
    West (Geo. M.) co. (Richmond, Va.)
    Woodward & Lothrop, Washington, D.C.
    Box 20: A - B
    Box 21: Cabell
    Box 22: Call - Gardner
    Box 23: Gentry - J
    Box 24: L - N
    Box 25: O - Rodgers
    Box 26: Roller - end
  - Accounts, 1896-1912, 38 items (Box 27)
    Chiefly with Harrisonburg, Va., merchants for a variety of household items.
  - Materials concerning the Colonial Dames of America in the State of Virginia. 1897-1912, 35 items (Box 27)
    Include Lucy Brown (Cabell) Roller's applications, dues notices, and correspondence, chiefly meeting announcements.
  - Materials concerning the Daughters of the American Revolution, Massanutten Chapter. 1898-1914, 5 items (Box 27)
    Include a resolution, 1914, on the death of Lucy Brown (Cabell) Roller.
  - Invitations n.d., 17 items (Box 27)
    Invitations to weddings and graduations, and regrets to a party hosted by Lucy Brown (Cabell) Roller and John Edwin Roller.
  - Visiting cards n.d., ca. 100 items (Box 27)
    Include several of Lucy Brown (Cabell) Roller's before her marriage, and cards of visitors to the Rollers during their first year in Harrisonburg, Va. (ca. 100 items).
  - Miscellaneous materials n.d., 5 items (Box 27)
    Include contracts and estimates for house repairs, and embroidery patterns.
- George Washington Cabell (1873-1943) papers, 1899-1920
  - Correspondence, 1899-1920, 26 items (Box 28)
    Correspondence of George Washington Cabell of "Inglewood," Nelson co., Va., farmer and justice of the peace. Chiefly letters of condolence for the deaths of his parents, Patrick Henry Cabell (d. 1907) and Betty Willis (Eubank) Cabell (d. 1907), and brother Patrick Henry Carey Cabell (d. 1920). Prominent correspondents include brother Royal Eubank Cabell (of Richmond, Va., while practicing law and working for the Liability Department, Traveler's Insurance Company) and sister Margaret Etta "Ettie" (Cabell) Matthews (of Danvers, Mass., concerning the illness of brother Patrick Henry Carey Cabell and her marital problems).
    Davis, T. C.
    Dunn, C. C.
    Dunn, E. C.
    Dunn, R. A.
    Fitzpatrick, J. T.
    Gordon, Bennett T.
    Johnson, J. E.
    Plecker, W. A.
    Turpin, John B.
    Independent Order of Odd Fellows. National Lodge #346 (Shipman, Va.)
    National Soapstone Co., New York, N.Y.
    Winn & Saunders, Broaddus, Va.
  - Accounts, 1911-1914, 2 items (Box 28)
    Include a list of accounts from W. M. Miller & Son, Inc., Lynchburg, Va., given to George Washington Cabell for collection.
- Margaret Etta (Cabell) Matthews (1876-1969) papers, 1888-1954
  - Correspondence, 1888-1954, 36 items (Folder 28)
    Correspondence of Margaret Etta "Ettie" (Cabell) Matthews, including letters from family and female friends, mostly concerning social and family life at "Inglewood," Nelson co., Va. Of particular interest are letters to nieces Elizabeth Henry (Roller) Bottimore and Lucy Cabell Roller, ca. 1905-1910, while Margaret and her husband, Nathan Matthews (1870-1936) were missionaries in Liberia.
    Elsie [?]
    Ethel [?]